David Warburton

Lexington, Kentucky | (859) 608-2068 | david.warburton@gmail.com Website: <u>www.rubbersoft.com</u> | LinkedIn: <u>www.linkedin.com/in/dwarburt</u>

Senior Software Engineer

Astute, solutions-focused applications developer and systems programmer, offering 10+ years of demonstrated experience in the semiconductors, IT services, and high-tech industries. Proven subject matter expertise in compiled and scripted languages, cloud architecture design, and systems administration. Specializing in full-stack applications, middleware development, and enterprise IT operations. Achieved N-tier application deployments, business process outsourcing, and executed complex software analysis and development solutions within global, Fortune 500 environments.

Exceptional technical and leadership acumen tuned for partnering with subject matter experts and key stakeholders to deliver on corporate strategy. First-rate skills in supporting large-scale software and systems applications from product introduction through end of life. Track record of success in managing complex projects and leading multi-site, crossfunctional teams.

CORE COMPETENCIES

Strategic Vision & Insight || Software Development Lifecycle || Cloud Computing || Cross-Functional Team Leadership New/Emerging Technologies || Agile/Scrum/Waterfall Methodologies || Big Data Analytics || Business Intelligence Resource Management || Systems Architecture & Design || Strategic Business Planning || Development Operations

<u>Technical Summary:</u> C, C++, C#, Ruby, Objective-C, Java, JavaScript, .NET (C#), Python, Drupal, PHP, Linux, RDBMS (MySQL and SQL Server), Bash and PowerShell, jQuery, jQuery Mobile, SharePoint, Application Development (iOS and Android)

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

INNOVATIVE ENTERPRISES/APPRISS INC, Remote, Lexington Kentucky

2018-Present

Senior Developer

- Mentored a large team of developers in modern development techniques and tools.
- Implemented CI/CD for backend systems using GitLab.
- C# Dotnet core development of backend systems and tools.
- Backend microservices system architecture design, development, and implementation in AWS.
- Design, planning, and implementation of Kubernetes clusters.
- Implement and maintain package server applications, e.g. a NuGet server, Docker packaging, etc.
- Develop and maintain tools in a variety of languages: Ruby, Python, JavaScript, Typescript, Java, and Elixir.

INTEL CORPORATION, Hillsboro, Oregon

2013-2018

Senior Software Development Engineer

- Played an instrumental role in driving software development solutions for a multi-platform, peer-to-peer communication protocol targeting mobile platforms and Internet of Things smart devices.
- Orchestrated cloud architecture, development, and deployment: designed and implemented an ejabberd and coturn server system for WebRTC signaling and authentication, using docker and jenkins for deployment.
- Managed a Jenkins server with 100+ projects and dozens of build servers. Leveraging additional programming expertise in C, C++, C#, Ruby, and JavaScript.
- Developed a native NodeJS module for interfacing with native code libraries.
- Spearheaded SDK design and development for NodeJS and SDK development in C and C#.
- Worked closely with APIs and clients. Designed APIs and documented them and managed the API documentation with various tools such as RAML.
- Create and consume XML documents using C++ RapidXML.
- Integrate OAuth authentication to Ruby on Rails web service
- NodeJS server side development and client application development via node-webkit.

ABLE ENGINE, Lexington, Kentucky

2012-2013

Senior Developer

• Drove and facilitated software development in web space (front-end and back-end) and app programming (JavaScript, Objective C, BrightScript). Drupal web sites, jQuery mobile web sites, and SharePoint development, with systems administration and production support responsibilities.

- Led large, complex projects and helped predict emerging customer needs and developed business strategies and innovative solutions to meet demand.
- Key member of 5-member, agile engineering team tasked with all aspects of designing, developing and supporting web-based software products.
- Key Technologies: Drupal, PHP, JavaScript, jQuery, jQuery Mobile, SharePoint, C#, Objective-C, linux, mysql

RUBBERSOFT, Lexington, Kentucky

present

Owner/Principal Software Engineer

- Delivered deep, broad-based software consulting services in web development and database technologies such as: Ruby on Rails, Wordpress, Drupal, NodeJS, MySQL, and couchdb.
- Orchestrated multiple software development initiatives. Communicated with release management status of new features and ensure they meet deadlines.
- Drove all software product features to completion within a release and reported status to key stakeholders.

XEROX COMMERCIAL SERVICES, LLC., Lexington, Kentucky

2012

Senior Specialist—Systems Development

- Led definition, development, testing, analysis, and maintenance of new and existing software applications and related systems development solutions using C#.
- Provided advanced application support to customers and charged with facilitating user training/support and streamlining automation of key business processes.
- Worked with senior leadership, management, and committees to develop and redesign systems and processes to improve the overall effectiveness of enterprise-level operations.

ESCENT TECHNOLOGIES, LLC., Lexington, Kentucky

2011-2012

Software Developer

- Drove design of leading-edge and highly available products and platforms. Supported Ruby on Rails web development, .NET 4.0 (C#) WPF Development, Systems Administration initiatives.
- Collaborated with team of distributed engineers and technicians to deliver complex software solutions.
- Established and implemented full cycle end-to-end development from design through implementation.

KEANE, Frankfort, Kentucky

2008-2011

.NET Web Developer

- Maintained and developed C# web applications backed by Oracle databases. PowerShell scripting.
- Designed, prototyped, and authored code for web components and applications based on functional specification and optimized tools for system performance.
- Worked with multi-site development team members with regards to sprint planning, release planning, and work prioritization across the cross-functional solutions team.

EDS, an HP Company, Winchester, Kentucky

2005-2008

Service Desk Analyst

- Answered phones in a cube farm and programmed pet projects.
- Instrumental part of 15-member team charged with launching new contracts within the company; served as subject matter expert across all contracts while resolving supervisor escalations.
- Redesigned help desk procedures to improve ticket handling and dispatching. Efforts resulted in XX% increased efficiency of the support team.

HYMENOPTERA INSTITUTE, Lexington, Kentucky

2003-2005

Programmer/DBA

• Designed genetics database and implemented web server solutions in PHP, Access, MySQL environments.

EDUCATION